# **KAYLA E. SMITH**

JUNIOR FULL STACK DEVELOPER (Barcelona, SPAIN)

kaylaesmith1@gmail.com +34 663 539 379 LinkedIn GitHub

#### PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a junior frontend developer, currently earning a diploma in full stack software development with Code Institute. I'm experienced in HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Python with some knowledge of React and Angular. After working in the Public Health sector as a researcher in Spain and the United States for over six years, I decided to broaden my skill set and embark on a career as a frontend developer. Until September 2022, I was part of the Tech Support Team at Oct8ne where I combined my love of language learning and problem solving..

## **KEY SKILLS**

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, React.

Databases: PENDINGLibraries: PENDING

Version Control: GitHub, Git, Heroku

Frameworks: Bootstrap, Netlify, PENDING

#### **EDUCATION**

July 2022 - present Code Institute

Diploma in Full Stack Software Development | (online) Credit Rated by the University of the West of Scotland

Sept 2012 – June 2015 Universitat Pompeu Fabra

Master of Public Health | (Barcelona, Spain)

Sept 2006 – May 2010 University of Iowa

Bachelor of Arts in Global Health & Spanish | (Iowa, USA)

## **PORTFOLIO PROJECTS**

Iowa State Fair – Three-page website about the Iowa State Fair.
 Technologies Used - HTML, CSS | GitHub - State Fair Project

Sea Creature Memory - Interactive memory game.
 Technologies Used - HTML, CSS, JavaScript | GitHub - Sea Creature Memory

Hangman – Interactive hangman game.
 Technologies Used - Python, Heroku | GitHub - Python Hangman

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### May 2021 - Sept 2022

### Oct8ne | Barcelona, Spain

**Tech Support** 

- Identify and solve technical issues that arise for customers.
- Improve the UI/UX through creation of custom designs and features for clients using SQL, Visual Studio and Angular.
- Impart basic technical information to clients to ensure seamless implementation and functionality of Oct8ne technology on their website(s).

## Sept 2013 - present

## Translator and Proofreader | Barcelona, Spain

Freelance

Translate from Spanish or Catalan to English for scientific documents related to healthcare. Editor for information
and use of English for scientific articles before their submission to scientific journals for publication.

## June 2017 - June 2020 Agend

#### Agency for Health Quality and Assessment of Catalonia | Barcelona, Spain

Public Health Researcher

- Write reports for the Spanish Ministry of Health concerning such topics as joints (shoulder, hip and knee) and enteral nutrition.
- Evaluate innovative projects and research proposals seeking financial assistance through public government funding.
- Create and disseminate reports and plans of action to local and national governments for Catalan healthcare facilities under pressure and time constraints dealing with the Covid-19 pandemic.

# **CERTIFICATES**

• SheCodes Online Workshops

(Introduction to Coding - Oct 2020; Front End Development - Dec 2020; React - Feb 2021)

# **ADDITIONAL INFORMATION**

- Currently learning React and completing the Code Institute course framework
- Languages: English (native), Catalan (C2), Spanish (C2), German (B1-B2)
- Based in Barcelona, Spain with residency and work permission for the EU and US.

## **INTERESTS**

- Women in tech groups (slack channels, MeetUps, etc)
- Collaborative coding opportunities (Hackathons)
- Cooking / Baking / Travel / Knitting & Crochet